joined now by the head coach of your
Cleveland Browns, Todd Monkin. And
coach, for you, the first draft process
as a head coach in the NFL. What's this
been like for you?
>> It's been great. It's been a
collaborative effort. Uh Andrew and his
guys have done a great job preparing for
uh this year, and we're excited.
>> As you always say, your wife says, just
call the plays that work. You tell
Andrew, just draft the players that are
good, right? Is that
>> 100%. It's really that simple. Make sure
we uh we draft players that uh that we
know are going to work out. And uh I
wish it worked like that all the time,
but we're excited about this year's
draft. Uh we've got a number of players
that we think really upgrade the roster
and then once we get them, we can't wait
to get them here and develop them.
>> What's the thing that you look for the
most as you kind of go through it
through this lens? Now you're looking at
both sides of the ball, but that you
want out of players who are going to
become Cleveland Browns.
>> Players that really like football
because if they really like football,
they'll love being a Cleveland Brown. If
they don't, they won't.
>> Yes. Six and 24, two picks in the first
round. So an opportunity really to get
better here tonight. What's it been like
kind of going through the process of
whittling it down to the guys that you
want and that Andrew that the team wants
to be Cleveland Browns and also some of
those scenarios that you go through of
hey if this is happening here's where
we're going to go and kind of the
preparation for it. How's that been as a
new experience for you?
>> Oh it's been great and I think we're
aligned pretty closely in terms of how
we see the roster. Let's start with
that. Our current roster and the holes
that we have and the players that we
think are going to be available at the
select at the spots we have. not knowing
how it's going to play out obviously in
terms of draft day trades, but again
there is a number of outstanding
football players that are going to
upgrade our roster.
>> In years past as an offensive
coordinator in the NFL, what was draft
night day one of the draft like for you?
>> Well, it it's completely different
because you're only looking at half of
the roster.
>> Sure. So, you're only looking
offensively at potential opportunities
to upgrade your roster, where you're at.
Uh, now the whole board comes into play,
the whole roster comes into play, where
we're at in terms of depth, where can we
not only feel like we're getting
starters and future starters for the
Browns, but where we can build depth and
and players we think that we can develop
into starters.
>> So, what are the butterflies like for
you? Because I imagine there'd be years
where you knew you were going to take a
defensive player in the first round and
so that wasn't really going to be all
that exciting for you as an offensive
coordinator. tonight. No matter who you
take, it's exciting for you. So, are
there a little Is this first draft as
the head coach of the Cleveland Browns,
first draft as a head coach in the NFL,
he's got to be a little juice.
>> I got juice, but no butterflies.
>> No butterflies. All right. Cuz you're
prepared, right?
>> Well, we're prepared. And Andrew is
making the pick. I mean,
>> come the first game next year, that's
different. I'll have butterflies, but
this is Andrew's deal tonight. And so,
I'm fired up. I do have juice. I am
excited. Uh, we did have a chance this
week to get outside with our players and
see what we have. and the opportunity to
add to that uh this weekend and then for
the most part get them all here in a
couple weeks is really exciting.
>> I'm glad you brought that up. What's
that what was that voluntary mini camp
like for you? We got to see, you know,
the first day the media was allowed to
be there, but over the last two days and
obviously ending today, what was that
like for you?
>> Well, first of all, the weather was
great to be able to get out there with
the guys kind of puts the cart before
the horse. Sure.
>> We went from phase one to phase three.
You normally you go from phase one
little bit phase two before you really
jump into offense versus defense, but
the players handled it great. The juice,
the connection, guys working together,
came out of it healthy, which is the
most important thing. I
>> remember one of the things you said to
me early on is you get better at playing
football by playing football and there
were a lot of team periods in the day
that the media was able to be out there.
I loved it. Is that something we can
expect a lot of as we go through OTAAS
and mini camp and then into training
camp?
>> No, for sure. They asked why why did we
have so many team periods? And I just
said because it's allowed.
>> Yeah, it was a great answer by
>> it's really that simple. I mean, why
would you not why would you not take
advantage of the opportunity? We did a
little bit of more of that today being
Thursday, but next week we'll get a lot
of routes on air, individual group work.
Why not get more teamwork when the rules
allow you to go against the defense?
There's nothing like it. The speed of
the game, the communication, the
situational football. Um, it was
invaluable.
>> It was awesome. And guess what?
Tonight's going to be awesome because
you're gonna add two, maybe more, may
who knows what we're going to see when
it all shakes out here tonight. But what
is a successful night for the Cleveland
Browns look like through your eyes
tonight?
>> Well, I don't think we're really going
to know. I I don't know that you're
going to know till you get the players
here. Y
>> I think one thing uh we all do and uh
the media does is we put grades on
players before we even let it play out.
I know we're going to get some really
good players. Y
>> and players that we need to develop.
We're in the developmental business.
That's what the NFL is. So, I'm looking
forward to whoever we select being
Cleveland Browns and then it's our job
to develop them. Uh bring them into our
team and then see what we got.
>> Oh, we can't wait to see who it is and
let you get your hands on them. Coach,
good luck tonight.
>> You bet. Thank you.